The gamble that took place
at Starside Hotel...
スターサイドホテルで
行われたギャンブル
それは人間競馬
...was a human horse race.
恐怖の鉄骨橋渡り
A bridge of fear to be
crossed on steel beams.
そしてカイジたちは馬
Kaiji and the rest
are the horses.
極限状況の中 修羅が始まる
A scene of carnage has begun
in this extreme situation!
人落とし　いけにえ
People fall!
Sacrifices for public execution!
公然の処刑
すまん 許してくれ
I'm sorry! Please forgive me!
やらなければ やられる
ならば…
If you don't push,
you'll be pushed. So...
落とす　ただ黙って…
落とす！
I will push!
But I will push silently!
カイジ 非情の決意
Kaiji is determined
to be cold-hearted.
Degradation
許されようなんて思わない
I won't seek forgiveness.
謝るようなことじゃないんだ
This doesn't require
an apology.
落とさなきゃ落とされる
If I don't push, I'll be pushed.
この仕組みは
この世の姿そのもの
This setup is exactly
how the world is like.
基本も基本　大原則だ
This is the
natural system of things.
カネやモノ　人やチャンス
Wealth, possessions...
People, chances...
ポスト 人脈　何だってそうだ
Positions, networks...
Everything is like that.
この世のすべてが有限である以上
奪い合いは当然
As long as everything
in this world is limited,
snatching from each other
is natural.
ぼさっとしていたら
次から次 みんな奪われる
Unless you pay attention,
everything will be
taken away by others!
失うだけだ　何も得られない
You'll have everything to lose
and nothing to gain!
だからみんな
死にもの狂いで取りに行くんだ
That's why everyone snatches from
each other as if to save their lives!
こっちから仕掛けていかなきゃ
失うだけ
Unless I make a move here,
I'll lose out!
だから攻める
That's why I'm going
to attack!
If I don't attack,
I'll be removed,
攻めなきゃ はじき出され
自分の居場所すら失ってしまう
and might even lose
my place in this world!
Snatch or be snatched from;
it's one or the other!
どっちかだ
取るか 取られるか
殴らなきゃ殴られる
If I don't strike,
I'll be struck.
いじめなきゃ いじめられ
If I don't bully,
I'll be bullied.
だまさなきゃ だまされ
If I don't cheat,
I'll be cheated.
裏切らなきゃ裏切られる
If I don't betray,
I'll be betrayed.
つまり
やらなきゃ やられるんだ
In other words, if I do nothing,
I'll be done for!
これは あらがうことのできぬ真理
This is the truth
that cannot be contested.
現実…
This is reality!
That's why I will push!
I must push!
だから押せ　押すんだ
It's nothing shameful!
恥じることはない
俺は俺のために押す
I'll push for my own sake.
Push! Push! Push!
押す　押す　押す
Right now, those in my way
are just my enemies!
今 俺の行く手をさえぎるものは
ただそれだけで敵
敵だ… 敵！
Enemies! Enemies!
Hence, as the time limit
of the game approaches,
そして このレースの終了間際
カイジは再び たどり着く
Kaiji once again sets off...
前を行く者の
その無防備な背中に
...towards the person in front
who can't defend himself!
ともしび
その背中 まさに風前の灯火
It looked like a candle light
flickering in the wind.
He can't stop shaking,
小刻みな震えが止まらず
ﾊﾞﾗﾝｽを保つだけで精一杯という
and just maintaining balance
brought him to his wit's end.
そんな状況の背中
In that very state,
there was no longer
a need to push.
もはや押すまでもない
どうかつ
一声 恫喝すれば
With just a shout, he would
lose his balance and fall.
それだけで
その危うい均衡は崩れ 落下
落下は避けられない
He will probably fall!
Fall!
落下… 落下する
He'll fall!
Helpless!
無力… あまりに無力な その背
That completely helpless back!
It's like a
powerless crying infant!
奈落のふちに泣く赤ん坊
What am I trying to do?
俺は何をしようとしている？
押さなければ押される
To push or be pushed...
Push or be pushed...
Push or be pushed.
押さなければ押される…
Push or be pushed!
But...
けど 押さない！
I won't push!
押さない
I won't push, I won't push...
押さない 押さない…
押さないんだ
I won't push!
押さなきゃ押されるとしても
押さない
Even though I'll be pushed
if I don't, I won't push!
俺は押さない
I won't push!
押さないんだー！
I WON'T PUSH!
バ… バカ野郎！
You fool!
押せ！そんなこと言ってる時か
Push him! It's not the time
to talk like that!
お前も押すな
お前も本心は押したくない
Don't you push, either!
You don't really
want to push either!
押したくないんだ
なら押すな
You don't want to!
So, don't push!
バカ野郎
本心もクソもあるか
Idiot! Is this where you
should talk about that?!
嫌でも押さなきゃなんねえんだよ
Even if you don't want to,
you have to push!
The goal is just
right before your eyes!
ゴールは目の前… 目の前だ
今ならまだ間に合う
どけ… どけ
If I do it now,
I can make it!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
俺は金が必要なんだ　どけー！
I need the money!
Out of my way!
押す　お前が押さないんなら
俺が２人押す
Push! If you won't push,
I'll push you both!
Die!
死ねー！
言ってたろ　お前言ってたろ
You said it, didn't you?
Didn't you?!
人を落とすなど狂気の沙汰だと
Pushing people down
is pure madness!
It's definitely madness!
その通りだ　狂気の沙汰なんだよ
お前は今 見失ってるんだ 自分を
目を覚ませ 目を
You have no idea
what you're doing!
Open your eyes!
黙れ　死ねー！
Shut up and die!
バ… バカ　よ… よせ
Fool! S-Stop!
よせ…
Stop it!
よせ
I-Idiot!
バ… バカ野郎！
Die!
死ぬ… 落ちる
Fall!
クソ クソ…
Darn... Darn it!
Darn it, darn it, you jerk!
クソ クソ… クソ野郎
失格だ！これですべて終わりだ
すべて…
You'll be disqualified!
Everything will be over!
Everything!
クソ野郎
You fool!
クソ クソ…
Darn... Darn it!
こうしてゴール寸前
And just like that,
inches before the goal,
橋に手をついた
カイジら３人は失格
Kaiji and the other two
touched the bridge,
and all three were disqualified.
賞金を得る権利を失う
They lost the right
to claim the prize.
結局 この修羅のレースを
制したのは
At the end, the winner
of this carnage is...
初っぱなのリードを
守りきった佐原
...the one in the lead
right from the start:
Sahara!
２位は
And then,
those in front and those who were
trying to catch up began to fall.
あとを追う者 前を行く者が
次々に落ち
結局 漁夫の利を
拾う形になった石田
Thus, Ishida managed to benefit
from it and emerge second!
第１レース
賞金のもらえる１ ２着は
In the first race,
these two arrived in first...
この２人で決着
...and second place
to receive rewards.
７人が落下して消えた
In the end, seven fell off
the bridge.
レース後 生還したカイジたちは
After the race, Kaiji and other
survivors were taken to an...
地下にある控え室で
すべてのレースが終わるまで待機
...underground room to wait
until all the races were over.
やった やった やった
I did it! I did it, I did it!
クソ クソ クソ…
Darn... Darn... Darn!
俺は… 正しかったんだろうか
Did I
Did I make the right choice?
それとも間違っていたのか
Or did I make a mistake?
おびえていたのか？
Was I just scared?
勇気があったのか？
Did I have the courage?
I don't know.
分からない
I don't know,
but what I'm certain of is...
分からないが確かなことは
俺はまた
得られなかったということだ
...that I wasn't able
to gain anything again.
またチャンスを
つぶしちまったんだ
Once again, the chance
had slipped from me...
また…
Again!
長く感じられたが 実質
橋の上にいたのは10分か15分
Though it felt like
a long time,
they were on the bridge
for just 10 to 15 minutes.
終わってみれば瞬く間
It ended in an instant.
10分ほどの間隔を置き
第２レースが始まった
And after a 10 minute interval,
the second race begins!
そして戻ってきたのは６人
Six people came back.
失意の４人と歓喜の２人
Four had lost heart,
and two were happy.
姿を見せない６人は落下
The six who fell
were nowhere to be seen.
レースを見なくても
ここに帰ってくる人数で
Even though they
didn't witness the race,
they could guess
what had happened...
そのレースの内容は
おおよそ想像がつく
by looking at the
number who'd returned.
第３レースは生還５人
第４レースは４人
There were five survivors
from the third race.
The fourth race
had four survivors.
そして最後 第５レースは…
And finally, the fifth race...
Something must have happened,
as only one person returned!
何があったのか
戻ってきたのは１人
ゼッケンを引きちぎられた男が
ただ１人
Only one came back and
his tag was almost torn off.
真っ青な顔で生還
The survivor's face was pale.
こうして11時35分
すべてのレースが終わる
Hence at 11.35pm,
all the races have ended.
60人の参加者のうち約３分の２
39人が落下した
Of the 60 who took part, about
two thirds or 39 people fell!
では早速 今日のレース
１ ２着の方に
Well then, as promised,
I shall hand out the reward...
...for today's race to the first
and second placed winners.
お約束のものをお渡しします
権利のある方は前へ
Those who qualify to receive it,
come forward.
では第１レースから順番に
Right, we'll start
with the first race.
おめでとうございます
Congratulations.
何だよ これは
What is this?
2000万および1000万の
チケットでございます
Tickets for 20 million
and 10 million.
どういうことだ
何だ これ
- What's going on?
- What's this about?!
ふざけるな 冗談じゃねえ
こんな紙切れ
Don't mess around!
It isn't funny! Why is it paper?!
出せよ金 現金で！
そうだそうだ！
Hand over the money!
Give us cash!
- Yeah, that's right!
- Exactly!
引き渡しは別の場所で行います
The exchange for that
will take place elsewhere.
チケットをお持ちの方は
私の後に続き外へ
Those with tickets must proceed
outside upon obtaining them.
外？
Outside?
なお第５レースで権利を得た方は
１人だったので
And since only one from the
fifth race qualified for a ticket,
今 1000万のチケットが
１枚残っております
there's still one
10 million ticket left.
３着以下 失格の方々も
Those placed third and below,
このチケットを
得られるやもしれません
and those disqualified
may be able to get this ticket.
ご希望の方は どうぞご一緒に
Those who wish to do so,
please gather.
そう言われたら
３着以下も行かざるを得ない
Upon hearing that, those who
came in third place and below...
...had no choice but to go.
結局 全員外へ
Eventually, everybody
went out.
その男の後に続く
They followed the man outside.
おめでとう　おめでとう
Congratulations, indeed.
Welcome, chosen ones.
ようこそ選ばれし者たち
おめでとう
Congratulations!
この男 希望の船
エスポワールのホールマスター
This man is none other
than the hall master...
...from on board
the ship of hope, Espoir:
利根川幸雄
Tonegawa Yukio!
この男がかんでるってことは
If this man is involved,
that would mean...
やっぱりこの橋も
例の船と元締めは一緒か
This bridge, along with
the ship and the party...
...are organised by the
same group of people.
諸君らは勇敢に戦い
その貴重な権利を勝ち取った
So, all of you battled bravely
to gain admission here?
諸君らは勝者
誇り高き勝者である
You gentlemen are winners!
Winners with pride!
実に素晴らしい
よせ
That is indeed splendid.
Stop this!
Who cares about that?!
そんなことは どうでもいいんだよ
つべこべ言わず出せよ 金
Stop talking and
just hand out the money!
そうだそうだ 金だ！
金を出せ
- That's right, the money!
- Hand us the money!
Yes, I'll hand it out.
出すさ　出すが…
換金の時間にリミットがある
But the time expiry for exchanging
the money is written...
チケット裏の有効期間を
確認していただきたい
...on the back of the ticket.
リミット？
Expiry?
[Expire Date]
[July 14th, 1.30am]
14th of July, 1.30 am.
ってことは あと２時間しか…
In other words,
only two more hours left?!
どういうことだよ これは
What is this all about?!
賞金なんて勝ったら即 渡すのが
当たり前だろ
Isn't it natural to get the reward
immediately after winning?
それをグズグズと難癖つけて
汚ねえぞ　ふざけるな！
Why are you playing dirty
by delaying us?!
Don't mess around with me!
減らず口をたたくんじゃない
You are in no position
to talk like that.
覚えておけ
今回の賞金を決するカード
Remember this well.
The ones who make the decision
to give rewards...
その切り札を握っているのは
こちら側だ
...and the ones holding the
trump card are on this side!
ついてきたまえ
Follow me.
時間は今言ったように
あと２時間弱
As mentioned just now,
you have only about two hours.
場所はスターサイドホテル
メインビルの地上22階
The location is at the
Starside Hotel's main building.
Go to the 22nd storey,
Room 2214.
2214号室
だが このホテルはオープン前で
But the hotel is
not yet in operation,
エレベーターは作動していない
so the elevator isn't working.
非常階段も閉ざされたまま
Also, the emergency
exit doors are shut.
その部屋へ行くのは不可能
Accessing that room
is impossible, and so...
だから我々で便宜を図り
道を通した
...for your convenience,
we have provided you a way.
フフ… お分かりかな？
Do you understand?
鬼が…
You devil!
フフフ　ここまでヒントを出して
ピーンときたのが１人だけとは
To think only one person
understood after so many hints,
どいつもこいつも勘が鈍い
it seems all of you here
aren't too bright.
おい
You!
Yes, Sir!
It is as you see.
見ての通りだ
チケットを金にかえる換金所は
向こう側
The only way to exchange
the ticket for money...
...is to get to
the opposite side.
ざわ… ざわ… ざわ…
な… 何だよ これ
W-What?!
バ… バカ野郎
T-That jerk!
終わったはずだろ？
もうこんなことは
Shouldn't this
have ended already?!
フフフ… あんなざれ事で
金を渡せるか
As if we'd hand you money
after something so simple!
あんなものは遊びだ
That was mere child's play!
パーティー客をもてなす
単なる余興
It was just to entertain
the party guests!
くっ てめえ！
You!
安くないんだ
2000万 1000万という金は
20 million or 10 million
is no mere sum!
勘違いするな ガキめらが
There's no doubt about it,
you punks!
金はな 命より重いんだ
The money is more
important than your life!
好む好まざるとにかかわらず
Whether they like it or not,
人は金を得るため
人生の多くの時間を
people spend most of their lives
working for money.
そのために使っている
言いかえれば自分の存在
命を削っている
In other words, one's existence
is wasted away for that purpose.
存在そのものを
金にかえているんだ
Your very existence
is exchanged for money.
サラリーマンだろうが
役人だろうが
Whether you're a salaryman
or politician,
みんな命がけで金を得ている
everyone uses their life
to gain money!
Think of the lives of
those supposed "elite".
想像してみろ　エリートと
言われている連中の人生を
小学 中学と塾通いをし
常に成績はトップクラス
They go to middle, high and cram
schools to get top class grades.
有名中学 有名進学校
一流大学と受験戦争に勝って
Then they go to top middle schools
and top universities...
...and succeed at
the entrance exams.
やっと一流企業に入っても
待っているのは出世競争
Even after finally entering
a first-class company,
they struggle to advance.
仕事第一と考え 上司にへつらい
取引先にはおべっか
They put their work first
in order to please the boss...
...and their business partners.
毎日 律儀に会社に通い
残業をし
Everyday,
they go to work religiously.
They work overtime and this
goes on for about 10 years,
そんな生活を10年あまり続けて
30代半ば 40…
till they are 30 or 40.
そういう年になって
やっと蓄えられる金額が
At that age, they finally have
assets worth 10 or 20 million.
1000万 2000万という金なんだ
分かるか？2000万は大金
大金なんだ
Do you understand?
20 million is a huge sum
of money. A huge sum!
それに比べて お前らは何だ？
Compared to that,
what are all of you?
必死に勉強したわけでもなく
懸命に働いたわけでもない
You neither studied hard nor
worked with all your might.
何も築かず 何も耐えず
何も乗り越えず だらだら過ごし
You're good for nothings.
You can't endure or overcome
anything and live wasted lives.
やったことと言えば
ほんの10数分の余興
What you just did was to provide
10 minutes of entertainment!
なめるな！あんなもんで
2000万という大金が手に入るか
How naive!
Thought you could get 20 million
for doing something so simple?!
ざわ… ざわ… ざわ…
それでも手に入れたい
どうしても手に入れたい
If you still want that sum
of money, no matter what...
となったら これはもう…
You'll have to risk
your very lives for it!
命を張る以外にない
ざわ… ざわ…
さあ目を覚ませ
渡れ　渡るんだ！
Open your eyes!
Cross it! You'll have to!
この機会を逃したら2000万なんて
もうお前らには生涯 手にできない
If you let this chance slip by,
you'll never get 20 million
for the rest of your lives!
渡れば今度こそ
何の条件もつけずに
If you cross it this time,
you'll receive the money
under no more conditions.
すっきり渡してやる　行け
Go, and take hold
of your future!
つかむんだ 未来を
ためらうな
さっきの橋と長さも太さも同じ
Don't hesitate.
It's the same length...
...and width as
the earlier bridge.
しかも今回は落とし合いじゃない
Also, you needn't
push each other this time.
向こうにたどり着いた者
全員に金を約束する
All who reach the other side
are guaranteed to have money.
つまり今回はレースじゃない
あくまで受け渡しだ
In other words,
this is no longer a race,
but a goal to reach!
自分のペースで渡れば それでいい
You may cross it at the pace
you're comfortable with.
どうした？グズグズしていると
放棄と見なし 全員失格にするぞ
What's wrong? If you dawdle,
you'd be seen as forfeiting...
...and be disqualified.
渡せ　確か２着のチケットが
１枚余ってるはずだ
I'll cross.
I'm quite sure there was
a 10 million ticket left.
それを俺に回してくれるなら渡る
I'll cross it if
you give that to me!
カイジさん…
フフフ 素晴らしい
Kaiji!
Wonderful. We welcome the
brave ones who open the path!
歓迎するぞ 道ひらく者　勇者よ
ざわ…
本気かよ カイジさん
今度失敗したら まぎれもねえ
Are you serious, Kaiji?!
If you fail this time,
it won't just be broken bones!
死ぬんだぜ 間違いなく
You'll die!
No doubt about it!
ざわ… ざわ…
フフフ… その点は覚悟の上さ
You must have such resolve.
勇者とはそういうもの
That is what it takes
to be brave.
ただし１つだけ断っておこう
However, there is a catch.
今回は…
Those who are disqualified
will not survive.
失格者の生き残りはないとな
さっきの橋では
バランスを崩したものが
On the earlier bridge,
those who lost their balance...
落ちずに橋にしがみついても
賞金の権利を失うだけで済んだ
...managed not to fall
by grabbing onto the bridge,
and merely lost
the right to the prize.
が 今回もそれを認めると
命がかかっているだけに
But if that were
allowed this time,
people would cling to
the bridge for their lives...
早々に勝負を投げて
橋にしがみつく者が続出
...rather than
press towards victory.
下手をしたらイモ虫の行進だ
Worst of all, they'd
inch across like worms.
興がそがれること はなはだしい
That would spoil all the fun.
そこで少し仕掛けを打った
So we have made
some preparations.
ざわ…
ざわ… ざわ…
フフフ 見てのとおりだ
As you can see,
the bridge is electrocuted.
橋に電流を流した
死なぬ程度のな
It won't kill you.
とは言っても
触れればショックは強烈
Then again, the electrical
shock would be huge,
体勢を保っていられない
and you won't be able
to maintain your posture.
落下は必至
You will surely fall.
手をつけば死ぬのだ
If your hands touch it,
you will lose your life.
いいかな？それで
Would that be acceptable?
くっ バカ野郎！話になるか
やれるわけねえだろ
You scum! This is ridiculous!
We'll never do this!
やる
I'll do it.
佐原 こんな話はもうねえのさ
Sahara, there won't be
another chance like this.
カイジさん…
金額だけじゃねえ
Kaiji...
It's not just about the money.
別の部分が異例なんだよ
It's the other part
that's the exception.
今回は俺が ただやればいい
渡りきればそれでいい
This time, all I have
to do is to cross.
I just have to cross,
and that's all.
誰も押し出さなくていい
I won't have to push anyone.
つまり… 競争じゃねえ
Therefore, this is not
a competition.
この条件は異例なんだよ
さっきやった橋に限らず
This is an exception.
It's not just the bridge earlier
but thinking of the world itself,
この世を利せんと考えたら
必ず他人と競争だ
there will always be
competition with others.
必ず他人を
押しのけなきゃならない
You always have to push
someone else out of the way.
この機会を逃したら
もうありゃしねえよ
If this chance slips away,
it won't come again!
今回みたいなこと
Not something like this.
ざわ… ざわ… ざわ…
フフフ… なるほど
面白い見方もある
I see. That's an interesting
perspective.
結構　理由は何でもいい
Good. It doesn't matter
what the reason is.
とにもかくにも参加は歓迎だ
In any case,
participation is welcome.
さあ 他にいないか？
腹を決めた者は
Right, are there any others
with the guts to decide?
不参加か　それもいい
無理強いはせん
No one? That's fine too.
We won't force you.
幸い１人は
参加してくれるようだし
There's at least one willing
participant, and that's enough.
それで十分　締め切ろう
I'm closing the entry.
E-Excuse me! If I cross this,
I'd get money for sure, right?
あっ あの… 渡ったら
間違いなく金はくれるんだな？
渡すとも
本当に… 本当だな？
I keep my word.
That's for sure, right?
二言はない
I don't repeat myself!
俺 やります！
I'll do it!
俺も
- Me too!
カイジが口火
Hey, hey!
Kaiji was the igniting spark.
それに つられるように
２人３人と参加を表明
After that, two or three others
expressed their wish to join.
バカか こいつら…
Are these guys crazy?!
分かってねえ
Don't they get it?!
今度の橋は
さっきの橋とはまったく違う
This bridge is not anything
like the previous one!
何でそれが理解できない？
Why don't they get it?
しかし2000万なんて大金はもう…
However...
20 million is a
huge sum of money.
７人　よし十分だ
これで締め切ろう
Seven people.
Alright, that's enough!
It shall close here.
待てよ
Wait!
クソ… まったく
どいつもこいつもバカばっかりだ
Darn it... Honestly...
Each of you is just a fool!
クソ クソ やるよ
やりゃあいいんだろ クソがー！
Darn it, darn it!
I'll do it!
I just have to do it, don't I?!
落ちれば即死　地上22階にかかる
ファイナルブリッジ
One wrong step leads
to instant death.
A final bridge,
at a height of 22 stories.
だがこの時 想像を絶する
At this time, however,
死の恐怖との戦いが
待ち構えていることを
Kaiji and the rest
have no idea...
カイジたちはまだ知らない
...of the battle with death
that awaits them!
ざわ… ざわ…
ざわ…
次回 ｢怪物｣
Next, Monster.